

CONTACT

Michigan, USA

J 440.739.0209

om benj.calderon@gmail.com 🔾

@benjcal

INFO

Full stack web developer passionate about performance and efficiency, with 6+ years of experience, and 4+ years working remotely. I am adamant about automating processes, lowering operational costs, and using the appropriate tools to solve the problem at

PUBLICATIONS

- You are Learning JS Wrong
- MobX & React for Vuex users
- Rust + Node.js are awesome!

https://medium.com/@benjcal

EDUCATION

MA Youth Leadership 2016 Andrews University

BA Philosophy & Leadership
2011 Antillean University

BENJAMIN CALDERON

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

EXPERIENCE

2017 – Present

Senior Full Stack Developer - 3ABN

- Lowered cloud services bill by 86% using open source solutions.
- Improved performance for essential computationally intensive algorithm by 80x using low level language (Rust + Node.js).
- Streamlined workflow and code management by migrating company code base from Dropbox to Git and implementing CI/CD.
- Optimized daily operations by automating manual tasks with cron and BASH.

2015 - 2016

Tech Lead - MotivatEdTech

- Led tech team to build a communication tool for MOOCs.
- Coordinated deployment strategies, outsourcing, and interns.
- Startup won a grant from Yale-NUS University.

2012 - 2016

Web Developer - Andrews University

- Saved hundreds of work hours by writing a migration script between two LMS using Python, BASH and unix tools.
- Optimized workflow for coworkers by automating HTML parsing to add custom elements to documents.

PROJECTS

Grades App - Grade management for teachers. *React, MobX, Webpack* https://benjcal.github.io/Grades https://benjcal.github.io/plum-grades_sketch

Student Landing Page – Tool for schools *HTML/CSS/JS* https://benjcal.github.io/mcs-startpage

html-cleaner – Tool to convert old HTML files to UTF-8 **HTML/JS** https://benjcal.github.io/html-cleaner

neon-init – Easy Rust + Node.js Integration https://github.com/benjcal/neon-init